Noah Taiga Endo Meier Sofware Engineer

noah.taigameier@gmail.com | +81-80-7382-4853 | Tokyo, Japan | German & Japanese citizenship www.linkedin.com/in/noah-endo-meier | https://github.com/Octosub

ABOUT ME

With a background in **analytics** and professional experience in **customer service**, I bring a **rich cultural perspective** and adaptability from my **bilingual upbringing**. Recently graduating from **Le Wagon**'s web development boot camp, I'm proficient in **Ruby on Rails**, **React**, and familiar with **modern workflows** of the tech industry. Now I'm **highly motivated** to apply my skills in Tokyo's IT industry.

PROJECTS

CIET - Can I Eat This? ⊘

Lead Developer

An application for foreign vegans/vegetarians in Japan to scan food products and check if it meets their dietary restrictions.

//Ruby on Rails, Google API's, DeepL API, Stimulus JS, HTML, CSS, Stimulus JS, Heroku

Power UP! *⊗*

A marketplace app where users can rent special powers from eachother. //Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Stimulus JS, Flatpickr, Devise

Mayaadaa Dana lanan Ca Ital

working environment

Movie Watchlist

This is a placeholder project to be replaced with a new project that I'll make soon.

SKILLS

| Backend | Frontend | Tools |
|--------------------------------|----------------------------|---------------------------|
| Ruby on Rails, Webscraping & | HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript | Git/Github, Heroku, Figma |
| API's, ActiveRecord & SQL, CSV | (Stimulus JS & React) | |

EDUCATION

| 01/2024 – 03/2024 Japan | Fullstack Web Development Bootcamp LeWagon Tokyo 9-weeks full-time intensive training of the technical skills needed for a successful career in tech, learning how to develop great products in teams using modern workflows at the #1 web development bootcamp in the world. |
|----------------------------|---|
| 2017 – 2022 Germany | Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy University of Konstanz Studied at one of Germany's eleven excellence universities with a focus on analytical philosophy and philosophy of the mind. |

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

| 10/2020 – 10/2020 Tokyo, Japan | Compliance Trainee • Learning about data protection of customers in accordance with the GDPR. |
|-----------------------------------|---|
| 06/2022 – 12/2023 Tokyo, Japan | Guidepoint Japan Research Associate • Conducting effective analysis on various topics to consult clients in a fast paced |

LANGUAGES

04/2020 10/2020

| Japanese | German | English |
|------------------------------|------------------------------|-----------------------|
| Native/Bilingual proficiency | Native/Bilingual proficiency | Bilingual proficiency |